<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Daniel Duan's Articles About Twitter</title>
        <link>https://duan.ca/tag/twitter/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://duan.ca/tag/twitter/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
            <item>
                <title>The Lazy Programmer&#39;s Guide to Single-user Mastodon</title>
                <description>&#60;p&#62;As of today, my identity in the &#38;quot;fediverse&#38;quot; has become &#60;code&#62;@daniel@duan.ca&#60;/code&#62;. This post was originally published
on &#60;code&#62;duan.ca&#60;/code&#62;. Pretty neat, eh? I achieved this by hosting a private instance of the open-source Mastodon
project. Here&#39;s my experience setting that up, and why it seemed harder than it is.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2&#62;What exactly did I achieve?&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I own the domain &#60;code&#62;duan.ca&#60;/code&#62;, which serves as the root of an existing website. I set up an functioning
instance of Mastodon with a single user &#60;code&#62;@daniel&#60;/code&#62;. This user is discoverable in other Mastodon instances as
&#60;code&#62;@daniel@duan.ca&#60;/code&#62;.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2&#62;How did I do it?&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;As someone who barely touch server-side programming, running a Mastodon instance seemed very daunting to me.
What database to use? How? What&#39;s the best way to host a Rails app? I need a email server? Where to host the
media files I post?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;There are a lot of step-by-step set-up tutorials on the internet. This post is, definitively, not one of
those. But having gone through the process of &#60;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.digitalocean.com/apps/mastodon&#34;&#62;setting up an instance on DigitalOcean&#60;/a&#62;, I end up with a few
tips and tricks to share! Let&#39;s through them:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ol&#62;
&#60;li&#62;If you have a DigitalOcean account, setting a server up is as simple as searching up &#38;quot;Mastodon&#38;quot; in their
market place as a step in creating your Droplet.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;You &#60;em&#62;do not&#60;/em&#62; need an email server for a single-user instance. Think about it, you have root access to the
database, what do you need email for? Verify your own identity? Spam yourself?&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;That said, Sendgrid is free for low-volume emails.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Ok, you ssh into your Droplet, the first thing you see is a guided CLI experience for setting things up.
Don&#39;t go through it just yet! For me, my root domain &#60;code&#62;duan.ca&#60;/code&#62; hosts an entirely different site. So I have
to pick a subdomain to host Mastodon. Make sure you set up an A record in your website&#39;s DNS for your
chosen subdomain. If this record isn&#39;t read, the guided setup will fail when it tries to get an certificate
from Let&#39;s Encrypt.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Unless you want to buy a new DNS service from DigitalOcean, your A record should be configured with your
existing DNS server provider! I needed a few minutes to un-confuse myself about this fact. DigitalOcean&#39;s
documentation makes it really hard to discover this fact.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;The only thing you need to get right is your subdomain, and the DNS record for it. In the rest of the
guided setup, you can make mistakes, and you can fix them later.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;I used an s3 bucket for media. s3&#39;s UX is kind of terrible, so if you are doing it for the first time, good
luck.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Instead of &#38;quot;admin&#38;quot;, choose your Mastodon username in the setup guide. This user does not have special
privilege for the site anyways, despite what the default name suggests. After this step, the guide will
provide you with a password, take note of that if you want to log in with this user later :)&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Again, you could figure out how to get an STMP server to send emails on your Mastodon instance&#39;s behalf.
But you are the only user, right? So you can just make some value up for all things SMTP/email related. At
the end, when the guide asks whether to send a test Email, choose &#38;quot;no&#38;quot;.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;The Mastodon code is located at &#60;code&#62;/home/mastodon/live&#60;/code&#62;. Most of the information is stored in
&#60;code&#62;.env.production&#60;/code&#62; in that directory. This is where you can change your mind/fix your mistake from the
guided setup. You can use Vim instead of Nano. (Although if you like Vim, you&#39;d probably find out
anyways).&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Mastodon ships with an admin &#60;a href=&#34;https://docs.joinmastodon.org/admin/tootctl/&#34;&#62;CLI tool&#60;/a&#62; &#60;code&#62;tootctl&#60;/code&#62;. It&#39;s located in &#60;code&#62;bin/tootctl&#60;/code&#62;.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Before attempting to run this tool, switch to user &#60;code&#62;mastodon&#60;/code&#62; by running &#60;code&#62;su mastodon&#60;/code&#62;. Otherwise, you&#39;d
be confused as to why you need to install Ruby stuff, and can&#39;t connect to the Postgres database.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;If the guide didn&#39;t tell you an error, and your values in &#60;code&#62;.env.production&#60;/code&#62; are all right, you will be
able to type your subdomain in a browser and see Mastodon! Log in with your username and password from
the guide. Upload a profile photo to test whether your media service is set up correctly.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;(DO NOT DO THIS until you finish the next step!) At this point, you&#39;d be able to go to an existing
Mastodon instance, and look yourself up! If your subdomain is &#60;code&#62;social.duan.ca&#60;/code&#62;, username &#60;code&#62;daniel&#60;/code&#62;, you
should be discoverable as &#60;code&#62;@daniel@social.duan.ca&#60;/code&#62; on a site such as &#60;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.social&#34;&#62;mastodon.social&#60;/a&#62; now. But if you
do this, that site may get confused, and permanently consider &#60;code&#62;@daniel@social.duan.ca&#60;/code&#62; as your fediverse
identity. So don&#39;t do that! Finish the next step.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;To use your root domain instead of this subdomain, you 301 redirect &#60;code&#62;/.well-known/host-meta*&#60;/code&#62; from root to
the real location. &#60;a href=&#34;https://masto.host/mastodon-usernames-different-from-the-domain-used-for-installation/&#34;&#62;this article&#60;/a&#62; explains it very well. Make sure to both set up the URL
redirect, as well as &#60;code&#62;LOCAL_DOMAIN&#60;/code&#62;, and &#60;code&#62;WEB_DOMAIN&#60;/code&#62; in &#60;code&#62;.env.production&#60;/code&#62;.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Make your user the owner of the site (RTFM). You&#39;ll see additional, site-wide settings afterwards. Make
sure to disable signup, either in the GUI, or with &#60;code&#62;tootctl&#60;/code&#62;.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ol&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That it! These may seem like a lot of tips, but I think, as a smart programmer, you can eventually figure all
of these things out pretty easily. I put them down here because, had I known these, I would&#39;ve saved a bunch
of times in the end.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2&#62;Why?&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Why spend the time, and money, to go through all of this?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This is a really good question. I &#60;a href=&#34;https://duan.ca/2022/11/20/the-social-graph/&#34;&#62;wished&#60;/a&#62; less people would
leave Twitter. I host my personal site/blog on my own domain, as opposed to using a Medium site or something.
So, if I have to &#38;quot;federate&#38;quot; my microblogs, why shouldn&#39;t I try to gain more independence? How many of these
mastodon instances can do better than Twitter, in terms of site maintenance, and content moderation? Instinct
tells me, something between self-hosting, and Twitter, might be the right balance. But I&#39;m here for the long
haul, and, if self-hosting proves to be the wrong direction, I&#39;ll pivot.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Until then, this has been fun.&#60;/p&#62;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 18:21:11 -0800</pubDate>
                <link>https://duan.ca/2022/12/10/lazy-mastodon/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://duan.ca/2022/12/10/lazy-mastodon/</guid>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Social Graph</title>
                <description>&#60;p&#62;From a purely personal perspective, connecting with people via the internet is good. I&#39;m grateful that services such as Twitter exist. Since the year 2008, a significant amount of my life happened on Twitter. The only important component of Twitter is the connections. I&#39;m lucky that some people like what I post. I&#39;m used to a small stream of thoughts from those I follow.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;These days, those I follow aren&#39;t posting much. They are posting on other websites. The connection I so depend on are broken. It saddens me. Therefore, I&#39;m forced to move to maintain the connections.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I have many thoughts. A tweet storm? Well, if the cool people are there to read it, sure. Knowing myself, I&#39;ll probably cross-post it to the many places where my people are. That&#39;s a hustle that I don&#39;t have the patience for. That saddens me, too.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, here we are, the good old blog post. Cross-posting a link is doable.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2&#62;The Twexit&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Remember when we make Brexit jokes about everything on Twitter? Good times! Here&#39;s what I think about the &#38;quot;Twexit&#38;quot;.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Thanks to email archive and 1Password, I found my mastodon.social login credentials. According to the site, I joined in 2018 (coincidentally, an exact decade later that me joining Twitter). 4 years ago was when me, and, more importantly, a lot of the people I follow on Twitter, first learned about Mastodon. They had their reasons to give it a try. They were my reason to give it a try. We did.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I honestly can&#39;t tell if this time is more different than that last time. We were, and are, voting with our feet.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;Warning: the following is a cynical take.&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;We are leaving this time, partially, because a lot of Twitter employee were forced to leave. They built the site for us, we are grateful for their work. We find them getting laid off / forced to change life style unacceptable, so much so that we... abandon the product they built for lesser ones.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Of course, that illogicality was based on some superficial analysis. An easier, logical path to follow, but also a harder truth to swallow, is that the Twexit, both times, were motivated by hate. Hate over a person that possess outsized influence on the platform.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;To hate is not wrong. Again, I don&#39;t have this reason to leave. Simply, I want to maintain my connections. I wish I shared the hate, though. Because that would&#39;ve made me less sad.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;(Perhaps &#38;quot;hate&#38;quot; is too strong of a word. Substitute it with the word you associate with the big personalities that drove you or your followees off to other platforms).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Will Twexit succeed this time?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I&#39;ve observed (to my relief!) that my timeline on Twitter hasn&#39;t completely died. It would&#39;ve been chilling to see it die (remember those empty streets during early COVID? NOT great, no). I hold out hope that better the user experience will ultimately prevail (more on that in the next section); and negative emotions alone won&#39;t sustain this round of Twexit.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2&#62;A Better Social Graph&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That is not to say &#38;quot;I hope everyone return to Twitter&#38;quot;. If Mastodon in late 2022 turns out to be a better product, I&#39;m happy to migrate/establish new connections there.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Now, I, the master of the Daniel-verse, will tell you what the best user experience for &#38;quot;social media&#38;quot;
could/should have been.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This text you are reading is originally published on a personal website composed of purely static assets
(mainly HTML, minimal amount of CSS, and essentially, no JavasSript). Critically, it also includes this
advanced technology called an RSS feed.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;If I have to psyco-analyze the young Danial from early 2010s (why not?), an important reason he became
hopelessly dependent on Twitter was the death of Google Reader. Prior to that event, the web service he
habitually check was not predominately Twitter.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Some of us remember how the connections were built prior to Facebook and Twitter. There were many sites that served similar purposes, sure. But there&#39;s also a community that subscribed to each others&#39; RSS feed. We commented on others&#39; posts, we linked and reposted, and commented on the comments. There were conversations, connections. An event that stood out for me during that era was when &#60;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larry_Wall&#34;&#62;Larry Wall&#60;/a&#62; commented on my post about his Perl book. You see, the connections included cool people, too.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, Google Reader. What if a API for posting comments for a web link became standardized? What if the RSS readers includes a text box for that API? What if everyone also include comments (ignore spams for now) in their feeds?&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Yeah, that would be, arguably, a similar experience to Twitter or Mastodon today. In fact, this isn&#39;t even
a new idea. The &#60;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/&#34;&#62;IndieWeb&#60;/a&#62; folks did their Twexit before Google Reader was killed. In
retrospect, they were smart as hell. We didn&#39;t follow their footsteps because Twitter turned out to be
a better user experience for people that don&#39;t own a website. Things could easily have played out differently,
though. Blogging and RSS could&#39;ve become more mainstream sooner. Web 2.0 could&#39;ve improved interactivity of
these blogs and feeds. Facebook and Twitter wouldn&#39;t have become so big of a deal.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Oh well.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;h2&#62;We Are All Indie Web&#60;/h2&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That&#39;s an inspirational statement. In this moment, I&#39;m more convinced of this inspiration than ever. More
Mastodon-like open-source software, more protocols such as ActivityPub, smarter economic structures for
content ownership. All of these, and more.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;In late 2022, this opening prose from the ancient Chinese book Romance of the Three Kingdoms keeps echoing
in my mind:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;blockquote&#62;
&#60;p&#62;...分久必合，合久必分&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;/blockquote&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Literally, it means &#38;quot;Long periods of division precede unity and long periods of unity precede division.&#38;quot;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;From Google Reader to Twitter to Mastodon, this tension between centralization and decentralization is oh-so-familiar. An equilibrium that could stabilize, IMHO, is a centralized user experience running on a decentralized infrastructure. Naively, that&#39;s a software thing. Realistically, it all rely on the collective mind of our social graph. Our connections forms the graph, the graph funnels in money, the money makes the good user experience. Sorry, money plays a role in the real world, like it or not.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;For now, though, I&#39;m happy to work to maintain my connections. I&#39;ll use many sites. I&#39;ll also try to become &#38;quot;indie&#38;quot;. Maybe I&#39;ll set up a feed for &#38;quot;microblogging&#38;quot;, and write some service to cross-post to those sites. Maybe I&#39;ll write my own mastodon-compatible ActivityHub implementation. Maybe these will turn out to be some more ill-fated personal projects -- that sounds awfully fun.&#60;/p&#62;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 13:06:48 -0800</pubDate>
                <link>https://duan.ca/2022/11/20/the-social-graph/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://duan.ca/2022/11/20/the-social-graph/</guid>
            </item>
    </channel>
</rss>