<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Daniel Duan's Articles About Twitch</title>
        <link>https://duan.ca/tag/twitch/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://duan.ca/tag/twitch/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
            <item>
                <title>Fall Guys are Among Us</title>
                <description>&#60;p&#62;I noticed a lot of people are playing these two games on Twitch recently: Fall Guys and Among Us.
Personally, I think Fall Guys is a pretty fun game to play and Among Us is an entertaining game to
watch. I&#39;m glad these games are out and popular in this strange year, even though I&#39;m not
playing either frequently (perhaps that&#39;s a mistake).&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Anyways, I want to write about this observation that seems unique from me: that the in-game
characters in these two games are both blob-y, short and colorful. This similarity stuck in my head
for a while, and I&#39;m getting increasingly anxious because those who frequently play these games
aren&#39;t making similar remarks &#60;em&#62;at all&#60;/em&#62;. So, in this Sunday evening, I just had to get it out of my
head:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;video id=&#34;video-tag&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; autoplay muted loop playsinline&#62; 
    &#60;source src=&#34;/assets/2020/08/FallGuysAmongUs.mov&#34; type=&#34;video/quicktime&#34; /&#62;  
&#60;/video&#62;
&#60;img id=&#34;img-tag&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; src=&#34;/assets/2020/08/FallGuysAmongUs.mov&#34;&#62;
&#60;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34;&#62;
    function BrowserDetection() {
        //Check if browser is Safari, if it is, hide the &#60;video&#62; tag, otherwise hide the &#60;img&#62; tag
        if (navigator.userAgent.search(&#34;Safari&#34;) &#62;= 0 &#38;&#38; navigator.userAgent.search(&#34;Chrome&#34;) &#60; 0) {
            document.getElementById(&#39;video-tag&#39;).style.display= &#34;none&#34;;
        } else {
            document.getElementById(&#39;img-tag&#39;).style.display= &#34;none&#34;;
        }
    }

    //And run the script. Note that the script tag needs to be run after HTML so where you place it is important. 
    BrowserDetection();
&#60;/script&#62;
&#60;p&#62;This animation is made from Pixelmator and Keynote. Those two along with Sketch and Final Cut Pro
make me feel invincible these days.&#60;/p&#62;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 23:42:44 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://duan.ca/2020/08/16/fall-guys-and-among-us/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://duan.ca/2020/08/16/fall-guys-and-among-us/</guid>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>StreamLogger</title>
                <description>&#60;p&#62;After turning off stream on &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitch.tv/daniel_duan&#34;&#62;Twitch&#60;/a&#62;, the first thing I normally do is
exporting the stream video to YouTube, so that the stream has an archive that
survives Twitch&#39;s short-ish retain policy.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;These videos, perhaps surprisingly, get a few views! It&#39;s not a lot by any
measures, but I&#39;m conscientious of the fact that a typical stream archive is
a multi-hour long video with no content curation, no clear schedule, and
it sometimes contains breaks. Needless to say, watching them after-the-fact
requires some (or a lot of) fast-forwarding.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;So, last week &#60;a href=&#34;https://twitch.tv/daniel_duan&#34;&#62;on stream&#60;/a&#62;, I set out to improve the fast-forwarding
experience. YouTube has this feature that lets you jump to specific timestamp
in the video through a URL parameter in the video&#39; link. Further, they generate
this parameter for text in video&#39;s description, if the text is in the right
format. This is handy for generating a &#38;quot;table of content&#38;quot; for the video so that
viewers can click the timestamp in the description to jump to the section they
are most interested in.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dduan/StreamLogger&#34;&#62;StreamLogger&#60;/a&#62; is a little utility that lets me note down what happened while
I&#39;m streaming. It&#39;s kind of like writing a commit message, except the message
describes what happened since the last &#38;quot;commit&#38;quot;. These messages, along with
their associated timestamps, will be used by StreamLogger to generate the &#38;quot;table
of content&#38;quot;. Using it in command line looks like this:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;pre&#62;&#60;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&#62;# Turn on stream, maybe check signs of being live, etc. Then
slog start # start a new log

# Do stuff, when it comes to a natural conclusion point...
slog -- &#39;I did stuff&#39;

# Do more stuff...
slog -- &#39;some other stuff&#39;

# Some time later... end stream
# No action is required to end the stream as far as StreamLogger is concerned.

# Now, to generate the table-of-content
slog stamp -s 1:32
&#60;/code&#62;&#60;/pre&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That last command outputs&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;pre&#62;&#60;code&#62;0:01:32 I did stuff
1:41:59 some other stuff
&#60;/code&#62;&#60;/pre&#62;
&#60;p&#62;... which goes to the video&#39;s description.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;There&#39;s a few subtleties in this overall simple tool.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Whenever a message is added, it gets associated with the time at which the
&#60;em&#62;previous&#60;/em&#62; message was add. So the act of logging marks both the end of
a chapter and the beginning of the next.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;In reality, there&#39;s always going to be a gap between the start of the stream and
the time the log is initialized. That&#39;s what the &#60;code&#62;-s 1:32&#60;/code&#62; in the last command
is trying to correct. It tells StreamLogger the length of the gap. Now the
absolute time associated with each event has a relationship with the archive
video.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;hr /&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I chose to write this in Rust because I&#39;m going to need the final product on
Linux, macOS, and Windows since I stream on all 3 platforms. (fun fact: I never
built it directly on my PC running Linux. Instead, I simply downloaded the
musl-based build from the GitHub release, which was built by GitHub Actions. It
works beautifully.) Maybe one day I&#39;ll add a GUI for it that works across these
platforms, too, so that it&#39;s more friendly to wider group of users.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;hr /&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The more I use and think about StreamLogger, the more I like it. You can see
me working its entirety in the following archives ;)&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Part 1: https://youtu.be/xWRcdaEjir4
Part 2: https://youtu.be/RS-ZMBzu9Dg&#60;/p&#62;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 12:36:55 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://duan.ca/2020/06/13/stream-logger/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://duan.ca/2020/06/13/stream-logger/</guid>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>TOML Decoder Playlist</title>
                <description>&#60;p&#62;I enjoyed making &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dduan/TOMLDeserializer&#34;&#62;TOMLDeserializer&#60;/a&#62; and &#60;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dduan/TOMLDecoder&#34;&#62;TOMLDecoder&#60;/a&#62; recently. Let&#39;s hope
some projects will pick them up and TOML as a configuration format will start to
spead in Swift communities.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What&#39;s outstanding about these projects is that I started working on them while
&#60;a href=&#34;https://twitch.tv/daniel_duan&#34;&#62;streaming&#60;/a&#62;. Personally, I consume a lot of content like this. So now people
can watch me writing Swift, too.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I&#39;ve been archiving recordings of these streams as much as I can. Here are the
links to these videos, each is around 1-1.5 hours long:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/XLLlCEfuFLw&#34;&#62;Turn TOML Test Fixtures Into XCTests With Vim Macros&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Ztq3K3cq8f0&#34;&#62;Passing TOML Deserialization Tests&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/GTCYSIc6n3U&#34;&#62;Finishing TOML Invalidation Tests&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/HP2Wzh8MVvg&#34;&#62;TOML Decoder: The Beginning&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/EZ7VpbrLkH0&#34;&#62;TOML Decoder: Filling In Missing Implementation Pieces&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/bISMVVWOHKg&#34;&#62;TOML Decoder: Adding The First TOML Decoding Strategy!&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/oOOS4bnhwx4&#34;&#62;TOML Decoder: Project Overview And Data Decoding Support&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/9yDtXsrMtbU&#34;&#62;TOML Decoder: Key Decoding Strategies&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;&#60;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/g1V872HL4Dk&#34;&#62;TOML Decoder: Project Updates&#60;/a&#62;&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;The TOMLDecoder projects would&#39;ve been capture on camera entirely if I weren&#39;t
such a streaming n00b and messed up a few streams. Hilarious.&#60;/p&#62;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 20:32:37 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>https://duan.ca/2019/03/10/toml-decoder/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://duan.ca/2019/03/10/toml-decoder/</guid>
            </item>
    </channel>
</rss>