<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Daniel Duan's Articles About FreeCAD</title>
        <link>https://duan.ca/tag/freecad/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://duan.ca/tag/freecad/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
            <item>
                <title>Padding a Squircle in FreeCAD 1.0</title>
                <description>&#60;p&#62;&#60;em&#62;I bought a 3D printer, and, as a result, got into 3D modeling recently. I&#39;m still super new to everything. From experience, this means I should write down things I&#39;m learning. The beginner&#39;s perspective is valuable to other beginners!&#60;/em&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;A &#60;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Squircle&#34;&#62;squircle&#60;/a&#62; is a square who&#39;s corners are replaced by curves with g3 continuity, which can be thought of as &#60;em&#62;really hecking smooth&#60;/em&#62; curves where the derivatives of the curve must also be smooth. In &#60;a href=&#34;https://www.freecad.org/&#34;&#62;FreeCAD&#60;/a&#62; 1.0.x, it&#39;s not immediately obvious how to sketch such a shape, in order to create solid shapes out of it. With the help of ChatGPT, and the internet, I figured out a somewhat cohesive way to do this recently. Now I need to write it down lest I forget!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;img src=&#34;/assets/2025/06/squircle-00-finished.png&#34; alt=&#34;Finished 3D shape with a squircle front profile&#34; /&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Our goal is to have a sketch of a squircle that we can use to pad or pocket to create 3D shapes. In the sketch, we want to first create the sides of the square that&#39;s straight, and connect them with the g3 curve, which can be done via the Curves workbench.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;But first, let&#39;s break down the squircle&#39;s geometry a bit. A squircel is both a square and a circle. Each side of the square has a straight line, it ends at a specific point, let&#39;s call it &#60;strong&#62;A&#60;/strong&#62;, where the curve of the circle begins. From this point, if you draw a line perpendicluar to the straight part, and repeatly draw it on every such point, the new lines will intercect at point &#60;strong&#62;B&#60;/strong&#62;. The length of the line &#60;strong&#62;AB&#60;/strong&#62; is the &#60;em&#62;radius&#60;/em&#62; of the squircle.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;img src=&#34;/assets/2025/06/squircle-01-radius.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image illustrating the radius of a squircle&#34; /&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;In FreeCAD, we want to include these &#60;strong&#62;AB&#60;/strong&#62; lines as guides. They will define both the straight lines on the side, as well as the correct space for the curves. The guide lines and the sides will form a cross shape. Make sure everything is symmetrical, and the &#60;strong&#62;AB&#60;/strong&#62; lines all have the same size.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;img src=&#34;/assets/2025/06/squircle-02-sketch-cross-shape.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the FreeCAD sketch of a cross outline&#34; /&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Note that the &#60;strong&#62;AB&#60;/strong&#62; lines are in construction mode represented by dashes.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Exit the Sketch. Switch to the Curves workbench, and select 2 of the 4 concrete edges from the sketch. Use the Blend Curve option from the workbench. And you&#39;ll get some funky looking curves connecting the straight lines, and it&#39;s represented by a &#38;quot;Blend_Curve&#38;quot; in the object tree.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;img src=&#34;/assets/2025/06/squircle-03-curve-unfixed.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of adding the blend curve&#34; /&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Select the &#38;quot;Blend_Curve&#38;quot; in the tree and tweak its Data fields.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Set &#60;code&#62;Auto Scale&#60;/code&#62; to &#60;code&#62;true&#60;/code&#62;.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Set &#60;code&#62;Parameter&#60;/code&#62; to &#60;code&#62;0mm&#60;/code&#62; for both edges.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;The new curve should smoothely connect with the ends of the sides that&#39;s close to the other straight side. If not, set &#60;code&#62;Reverse&#60;/code&#62; to &#60;code&#62;true&#60;/code&#62;.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Most importantly, set &#60;code&#62;Continuity&#60;/code&#62; for both edges to &#60;code&#62;G3&#60;/code&#62;.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;&#60;img src=&#34;/assets/2025/06/squircle-04-curve-fixed.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of fixed blend curve&#34; /&#62;&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;That completes 1 of the 4 corners. Repeat for the other 3. And now you have a 2D squircle!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;There should be 4 &#38;quot;Blend_Curve&#38;quot;s in the object tree, as well as the original sketch.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Now things get a little convoluted. Although things on screen look like a closed wire, we can&#39;t use it to create a 3D shape for 2 reasons:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ol&#62;
&#60;li&#62;the &#38;quot;Blend_Curve&#38;quot;s aren&#39;t part of any body.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;the curves and the straights don&#39;t belong to the same geometry.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ol&#62;
&#60;p&#62;There&#39;s a easy way to fix both problems, thanks to the fact that multiple shapes in FreeCAD 1.0 can comine into a single sub-objects shape binder.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Switch back to the Part Design workbench. Activate the body you want the final 3D shape in (can be an existing or new body). Select all 4 blend curves in the object tree, and the sketch. You should see the entire wire highlighted in a uniform color. Then use the sub-objects shape binder tool, which gets you a single binder in the tree of the active body.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;You should see the binder on screen. Hide other things if they are distracting you. Now, select the edges in the binder -- all 8 of them! After that, you can use the Pad tool to create a 3D shape. And that&#39;s it!&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;hr /&#62;
&#60;p&#62;Obviously, a squircle is the simpliest shape to incorporate a g3 continous curve. But once we have the curve as a wire, anything is possible in FreeCAD.&#60;/p&#62;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                <link>https://duan.ca/2025/06/15/padding-a-squircle/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://duan.ca/2025/06/15/padding-a-squircle/</guid>
            </item>
    </channel>
</rss>