<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Daniel Duan's Articles About Windows 8</title>
        <link>https://duan.ca/tag/windows-8/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://duan.ca/tag/windows-8/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
            <item>
                <title>Windows 8 First Impression</title>
                <description>&#60;p&#62;I use KDE on Arch Linux for 80% of the time, OS X the other 20%. But I
got a copy of Windows 8 Pro for free as student so I decided to install it
along with Visual Studio 2012 Ultimate so that if I ever need to develop on any
Microsoft platforms, I&#39;ll have the environment ready. I jogged down these
impression after about a 30 minutes trial.&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What I didn&#39;t like:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;I have to use a .iso file the hardway (in my case, burning it to an
usb drive)even if I only wanted to upgrade from Windows 7.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;When upgrading from Windows 7, only the free space is counted as usable
for the new system, which means upgrading is not an option for I have a
mere 26G partition reserved for Windows.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;The old Mobile ATI graphic card driver stopped working after installation.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Apps don&#39;t share same session between the tile and deskop interface.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Contacts from different accounts (in my case, facebook and twitter) are
mixed together and there doesn&#39;t seem to be an easy way to filter them.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;I signed in with a Mircrosoft account for the operating system. But when
I started Visual Studio, it asked me to sign in with the same account.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;What I did like:&#60;/p&#62;
&#60;ul&#62;
&#60;li&#62;The tile interface looked nice.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;IE10 is fast. Looked particularly smooth under the tile interface.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;For an old machine I installed it on, the whole system is very responsive.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;The tile interface is not unintuitive. When in doubt, one of these actions
always gets me where I wanted:
&#60;ol&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Mouse to upper-right corner.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Mouse to upper-left corner and then move down.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;li&#62;Press the Win key on keyboard.&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ol&#62;
&#60;/li&#62;
&#60;/ul&#62;
&#60;p&#62;I&#39;m not going to speculate on whether the general public will love or hate
this version of Windows. But one thing is for sure: there is going to be an
reaction. I can see it go both ways.&#60;/p&#62;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 23:59:59 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://duan.ca/2012/10/27/windows-8-first-impression/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://duan.ca/2012/10/27/windows-8-first-impression/</guid>
            </item>
    </channel>
</rss>